A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Transportation, 2009-2013
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Secretary of Transportation, 2009-2013
The Library of Virginia
51147
2 cu.ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia. Office of the Secretary of Transportation
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 9 January 2014 by the Office of the Secretary of Transportation, 1111 East Broad Street, Room 3052, Richmond, Virginia, 23219.
Historical Information
Governor Robert F. McDonnell appointed Sean T. Connaughton to serve as the Virginia Secretary of Transportation in 2010 and he served until 2014. Richard D. Holcomb served as Commissioner of the Department of Motor Vehicles and Gregory Whirley as Commissioner of the Department of Transportation.
Scope and Content
Records, 2009-2013, created and maintained by Secretary of Transportation, Sean T. Connaughton, during the administration of Governor Robert F. McDonnell (2010-2014). The records include agendas, correspondence, decision briefs, memorandum, presentations, programs, reports, studies, and other working papers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2010-2013
Series II: Dept. of Motor Vehicles, Special Projects and Studies, 2010-2013
Series III: Dept. of Transportation, Special Projects and Studies, 2009-2013
Series IV: Miscellaneous, 2009-2013
Contents List
- Series I: Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2010-2013., Extent: 1/2 box (.50 cu. ft.). (Box 1)
  Series I: Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2010-2013, is housed in a half a box and arranged chronologically. Included are decision tracking sheets with attached correspondence or memoranda detailing the topics. Topics include support for changes to the Washington Metropolitan Airports Authority Board of Directors; Transportation Opportunity Funds; DMV Holiday closing schedule; Virginia compliance with Federal regulations; Interstate Route 95 tolls; Federal Real ID Act; and Recognition letters to staff, among other topics.
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2010 January-April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2010 May-July (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2010 August-October (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2010 November-December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2011 January-February (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2011 February-April (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2011 April-July (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2011 August-September (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2011 September-December (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2012 January-April (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2012 May-December (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2013 January-April (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Decision Briefs and Memoranda, 2013 May-December (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series II: Dept. of Motor Vehicles, Special Projects and Studies, 2010-2013., Extent: 1/2 box (.50 cu. ft.). (Box 1)
  Series II: Dept. of Motor Vehicles, Special Projects and Studies, 2010-2013, is housed in a half a box and arranged alphabetically by folder title. This series mainly includes correspondence detailing customer issues, closings, and operating hours. Richard D. Holcomb served as Commissioner of the Department of Motor Vehicles.
  - Customer issues, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Customer issues, 2010-2013 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - DMV closings, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hiring requests, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Motor carrier issues, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Operating hours, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Operating hours, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
- Series III: Dept. of Transportation, Special Projects and Studies, 2009-2013., Extent: 1/2 box (.50 cu. ft.). (Box 2)
  Series III: Dept. of Transportation, Special Projects and Studies, 2009-2013, is housed in a half a box and arranged alphabetically by folder title. Includes correspondence, memoranda, and reports detailing a variety of topics. Topics include the I-66 Multimodal Study inside the Beltway; Midtown Tunnel in Portsmouth; PPTA Implementation manual and guidelines; and a study of tolls on I-95, among other topics. Gregory Whirley served as Commissioner of the Department of Transportation.
  - Commonwealth Transportation Board (CTB), Issues, 2010-2012 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 2010 January-February (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2010 February (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - 1-66 Multi modal Study, Interim report, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - I-95 Tolling, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Mid-Town Tunnel Project (MTT), 2012 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 2010-2012 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Public Private Transportation Act 1995 (PPT), 2010-2012 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - Public Private Transportation Act 1995 (PPT), Bills, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Telegraph Road, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Tiger Grants, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Transportation Partnership Opportunity Fund (TPOF), 2009-2013 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous, 2009-2013., Extent: 1/2 box (.50 cu. ft.). (Box 2)
  Series IV: Miscellaneous, 2009-2013, is housed in a half a box and arranged alphabetically by folder title. Topics include aviation and the Metropolitan Washington Airport Authority.
  - Aviation, 2010-2013 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Gifts, 2010-2013 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Metropolitan Washington Airport Authority (MWAA), 2009-2013 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Proposed budget, 2012-2014 (Box 2, Folder 22)